we're gonna go to the text and do some
of the text we had talked about six main
negative emotions five of them are
called not not viewpoint of your world
and the last one is a viewpoint of your
world oh you got you guys got it
[Music]
shoot choke okay ch ug s CH u GS space m
CH yeah good that's it okay so we're on
the fourth one of the viewpoints okay we
did five negative emotions that are not
viewpoints and then the sixth negative
emotion the big one it has five negative
viewpoints inside of it let's go over
some of those those five first one was
destruction view which is the wrong idea
about me and my things okay
wrong idea about where I come from
second one was extreme view and for
example either
I am permanent or I don't exist at all
or I exist from my own side or I don't
exist at all okay third one was thinking
my wrong ideas are the best which is a
third kind of view and then today we're
on the fourth one fourth one is called
thinking mistaken kinds of practices are
cool okay
and this was kind of very popular in
India a long time ago and we'll talk
about it here suitum don't choose to
shoot songs in nee this is called
thinking that kinds of morality and
tapas difficult spiritual practices are
the best generally morality is the best
but it's wrong morality okay so we're
going to talk about it kung by Yoshiki
generate searching them there's a
practice in India where if you hold your
arm up for years you will reach nirvana
okay this arm gets very skinny and so
they try to hold it up for most of the
day for many years and then this arm
gets you can't move it much and and they
think that this kind of hurting your
body is some kind of religious practice
okay
another example is a manga Demba may god
damn bomb means it's like you do a fire
offering which we're gonna do tonight
and you sit in front of the fire but
then you build four fires around you so
you are inside of four fires in front of
a fifth fire and it's very very painful
and you know they think this is
spiritual this is a spiritual thing I
think Christians have a thing in the old
days where they will whip themselves
with some nails or something and like
hurt your body okay don't say some don't
say some Keaton dojo then there was a
weird Indian religion many years ago
where you do your practices you do your
prayers
and you dig a big hole and you put a
three-point spear up right in the hole
so it looks like that the points are
sticking like that and then you jump
into the hole and you try to get the
spirit to go here here and here and you
commit suicide with one one part through
your head and two parts through the
shoulders and then this is considered a
way to get to Nirvana yunxi tower to
shook I didn't know what this was I
looked it up this is some kind of weird
thing where you dress up in animal fur
and you act like that animal and it will
prevent you from going to that lower
berth okay like you barked all the time
or you wear a dog coat or something like
that okay and then he goes into it a
little bit gosh I keep my shirt on
Metheny so some people get a little bit
of correct vision into their last line
saying I'm a q-tip or Tony
then they saw that in their left last
night they were a dog and they get this
strange logic okay if I was a dog in my
past life and I died and I became a
human in this life then the way for me
to become a human in my next life is to
pretend I'm a dog in this manner they
get this strange idea okay
meaning the big Quique they bark like a
dog
teach a dog so they wear a collar and
all the dogs things so charging Mambo
tongue tilicho to suni and they try to
act as much like a dog as they can
membership a dog they assume a certain
number T and they keep this quote this
isn't morality for them called dog
morality
and Joe chicky cured sword zimba and I
think this will free them from from
samsara
okay Sun solar and to us it looks stupid
but probably we are doing some things
like that you know probably probably we
also have some ideas like that and in
the reading what's the item number nine
yeah it's young guys doing graffiti so
they are painting walls it's a legal
right in most places you're not allowed
to do it and what it means is you're
supposed to be I remember my teacher
telling me I can remember chili you know
you're supposed to save every living
being you're supposed to help every
living being but you are one of them
you're also one of every living being
okay
then I think sometimes we forget you
know we focus on other living beings we
focus on taking care of other living
beings and we forget that we are also a
living being so this is the idea where
they say your body is like a temple
and you should take care of your body
and and you should take care of your
mind because you are also one of all
living beings so you know you should eat
well you should rest enough and you
shouldn't think of yourself as something
impure or or someone who's not capable
many people spiritual people they think
I'm a bad person
or I'm not very capable my meditations
not so good I don't keep my sixth x book
I remember many years ago I taught a
young man he was from Burma
did you know him he's studying in how he
came from my job but you know he used to
have this idea that he was he wouldn't
take care of himself he said what's his
unki that's not like that and every time
I taught him like if I taught him the
six times book he was upset and he said
now you gave me another reason to feel
guilty every morning I just have all
these reasons to feel guilty every
morning and I'm a bad person and you're
supposed to be helping me but you keep
giving me things to do every morning and
now it's new things to feel guilty about
like now I didn't do my meditation I
didn't do my six times Burke you know
all these things you're teaching me it's
it's just one more thing that I'm not
doing okay so this kind of hurting
yourself is against this viewpoint okay
this viewpoint where you hurt yourself
it's not that you are sticking a spear
through your head it's that you are
constantly thinking you are not good
enough you're not special you are not
practicing well okay you get more and
more teachings and it seems like you're
worse and worse person
there's a famous meditation thing they
say if you start to meditate you will
find that your mind gets worse and the
student came to the teacher and said
after you taught me meditation my mind
got worse what the teachers say
it was always bad your mind was always
bad you didn't notice it before you're
actually improving okay so I think this
is not some kind of crazy viewpoint
where we are jumping on Spears or
something like that or we are whipping
ourselves we tend to beat ourselves up
in English we say be das awesome we we
don't respect ourselves but if you are
here and you came to them already you
are one and I don't know ten million
people okay and you don't feel special
you feel like a normal person especially
when you have a bad morning you don't do
any practice at all and you feel like
pretty normal and you don't feel special
but if you're here you are special and
you can't say you're not you are okay so
don't beat yourself up that's also
hurting the temple which is your your
body your mind okay we're not allowed to
hurt this temple when you criticize
yourself all the time sometimes you can
okay but not all the time okay
you are like spraying graffiti on the
temple you are making the temple dirty
okay you are a beautiful temple your
body your mind is a beautiful temple and
you have to admit it okay you're here
you know and you don't feel like oh I'm
the most special person in my country or
something but you are okay so I
appreciate yourself okay otherwise you
are breaking this viewpoint
okay okay of course you're a bad person
but sometimes you do good things not
just kidding
if you're here you're very strange
you're very strange and you're very
special and you have better chance than
anyone in this world in your life okay
you have a better chance than anybody
okay
number number five I think right Lata
say look Don lope that means wrong Vyas
and I'm gonna list some of them danshi
you don't believe in the for higher
truth it's not true that my whole life
is pain it's not true that I can stop
the pain it's not true that it has a
cause it's not true that there's a path
okay
these are not true or 0.03 joules some
ball it's not true that there are people
who escape from this pain and it's not
true that there is a method it's not
true that you can see emptiness directly
okay it's not true that there are people
around me who have seen emptiness
directly Sangha okay
Mende it's not true though if I do a
small good deed I can get a huge good
result karma and its growth the growth
of karma is not true
okay these are all locked on you know
and if you got in a room with somebody
if you got in a room with Geshe Michael
and get you Michael says do you believe
in karma you say yes cuz you know I
believe in karma and then then we go out
and say something bad to somebody you
know five minutes later
so there's believing in karma in your
words and there's believing in karma in
your actions right so of course all of
us tell people we believe in karma
we are Buddhists right but then we do
things that looks like we don't believe
okay
nepeta the sold on Shyam eppela yep and
don't over Dona Paula member tomma
chaplet Khun Danai then there's a very
famous thing in Buddhism especially mind
only school called John Doerr concordant
who wants to try word for zero dollars
yeah yeah I keep thinking about this the
wife comes home and her husband is
texting and he looks really happy he's
laughing and she walks into the room
suddenly and then wow cool now I forgot
my example oh he's texting she comes in
the room suddenly he hides his phone
right and then she's suspicious because
he looks so happy if you ever had this
problem you know what it feel it feels
really bad oh the husband is somebody's
really making my husband happy and then
you get really jealous you know and that
night when he's asleep you check his
phone to find out what's his other
girlfriends name and you find out he was
on Alibaba what's the other one
Alba Taba he was buying you a birthday
present
he wasn't texting his other girlfriend
and he was so happy because he was he
was thinking about how happy you're
gonna be when you get the birthday
present okay
but you had this this is called dong
dong dong dong means you make a big
story about something which is not true
the whole thing is not true what's the
biggest drunk dog in the kitchen my
husband decided to yell at me my husband
decided to yell at me okay that's where
this yelling come from he saw me
open the door then he had a thought in
his mind
I will criticize my wife I will call her
fun dong okay
like that's John Doe okay so don't dog
means it's not true but you make it you
make a big thing about something which
is not true okay and we do it about
everything okay
every time someone criticizes us we are
done dong okay
we are done we are making a story about
why they criticize us which is not true
okay actually coming from my seats okay
everything is coming from my sis what's
a corn damn can you get me a corn up in
the kitchen Arnhem
yeah okay so you walk in the kitchen
your friend is there your your friend
says your husband doesn't exist from his
own side and then you decide he doesn't
exist at all okay that's classic
condom which months more common in human
nature first ones more common okay you
think the husband decided to yell at you
but actually is coming from your seats
okay
the only people who think that nothing
exists in the world and therefore they
can do what they want they have no
morality it's a people who got a bad
emptiness teaching okay people who got a
bad emptiness teaching from someone then
they say okay nothing exists nothing
matters I can hurt people doesn't matter
okay okay children pegasi Khajiit nd cam
Dukey Jupiter chip adam chun jung-bae a
janitor neo cheney cute so shepard on
then he gives some examples of religious
Rondon and he's talking about ancient
Indian religions one is called Vishnu
and they say Vishnu created the world he
did ten different things and then he
created all the things in the world or
the Sankhya school says that there are
twenty five divisions of existence and
they were all created by some what do
you call it primal primal power okay and
then there's another school that talks
about a god named Ishwara
and they said everything was made by
this person then you asked them or who
made the person and they're like nobody
made the person so you're like so things
were made by someone who was never made
yes so things were made by a person who
never changed yes
so when a person makes something they
don't have to change yes
but by making something hero has changed
okay anytime you do anything you change
okay so these are all gone dog this idea
that someone who has been here forever
has made the world okay but never
changed okay gonna be coming on and
Dayton to town got cheated see paid to
theta so in German Italian to go so he
says yay we finished the sixth major
negative emotions five are not
viewpoints and five are viewpoints okay
the sixth one has five viewpoints inside
okay Dana they discuss occupant on your
boat engine can she Giovanni so if you
get one of these negative emotions you
should use the antidote you should use
the medicine for it okay when can she
couple a and then equals I edema four
hundred versus the lovely Hwang Jindo
Tim beaucoup non-negative this is really
interesting and it's difficult to
explain so in the Heart Sutra for
example make me nom-a-nom
new me email okay you don't have eyes
you don't have ears you don't have nose
you don't have tongue you don't have
bunny okay and you don't have mine okay
so there's six consciousness six parts
of you then if you think about it
the first four live on number five okay
your ears your eyes live on your body
your ears live on your body your nose
lives on your body your tongue there's
on your body so the first four one two
three four live on number five number
five is the home and the eyes lived
there the ears live there
so that's what this first line means
little do want you should do all the
powers of the body live on the body and
in the same way all negative feelings
you can have live on misunderstanding
your husband okay
all negative feelings these six cannot
exist without misunderstanding
so misunderstanding is like the home
base like the body and then your eyes
ears nose tongue these are all like you
all your negative emotions okay they
cannot survive without a place to stay
and anytime you have a negative emotion
there's misunderstanding under it okay
and that's really interesting okay and
I'm translating tsongkhapa's combo
Dobson it's his greatest explanation
emptiness we're halfway through it took
five years it's 750 pages we have to
send it to somebody by the way okay it
will be 1500 pages he was just using he
was just quoting this you can't have
anger or desire hatred jealousy pride if
you don't misunderstand things around
you
okay cannot cannot have you can't have a
nose without a face see it I mean that's
the idea okay alright some but our team
okay no motion Tom general captain Gucci
be misunderstanding your life spreads
through all of your negative emotions
and causes them dang ones in cowboy talk
to chasten and it but it's difficult to
see how misunderstanding is always
present when you feel negative emotions
so he said oak touch a word or two check
yeah I'll cover it later he says it's a
difficult it's difficult to understand
every time you have pride every time you
have anger every time you have addiction
it has to be that you are
misunderstanding that person or that
food or okay
you must be so he's gonna talk more
about it later okay
we reach the second category which is
how do negative emotions start up in
your heart okay how did they start up in
your heart but I'd like to I'd like to
take a break before we cover that we
have about 40 minutes I think and let's
do some more review of the old London
the last eight years okay so I'm on
number 88 what's the picture number 88
huh it's the dog helping the little girl
cook the cake okay you okay you guys
with me you want me to wait if your
woman is hmm doesn't look like it okay
I'll wait
let me know when you guys want to start
sure yeah everybody
Peter stop throwing things back there
yeah yeah all right all the troops are
quiet
say sub J okay la même has many many
subjects
I think our review of the long room if
you want to be alarm specialist
meditation masters degree in your ACI
teacher training I think it's about 800
items you're gonna have to know okay
total and but those have a sub J what's
a sub J word do you yeah they have a
certain order okay do you have a certain
order so like when you're working on a
car you're trying to fix a car there's a
certain order of things you should do
one after another and working on your
mind has a certain order okay you can't
just take a piece out of the alarm room
and do it randomly okay they're all nice
practices they're all good practices but
they have to be done in a certain order
okay ABCD okay and so in the long run
that's called subject the order of the
practices like first you should find a
teacher and then you should think about
your the good chance you have then you
should be meditating on death so I think
I don't know in America there's three
kinds of people I mean one is they just
go
anywhere and they learn anything they
hear they just go to any yoga class or
any retreat center and they just do
whatever the people are doing and then I
guess secondly there's people who learn
lamb rim but they kind of mix it up they
just do one thing and then they do
something but the best way is to do it
in the proper order
okay so your mind has to be changed in a
certain order and that's called subject
okay so that's an important thing about
lahrman you should learn it and you
should follow the subject okay the next
89 is called the forum magnificence the
four super cool four kinds of super cool
and recently they found this photo of my
teacher it's really nice this was some
of his first classes in the United
States I guess it was 1974 something 75
and I like how he's touching the planet
it's like he has some plans so I'm going
to read you this section from the from
the lamrim hang on
to consummate a matured zipper pajama
so traditionally at the beginning of
teaching timonium you talked about how
cool was the people who started love em
in this world okay and mainly we we
talked about Lord etosha okay so we call
cool source magnificent source okay so
it's traditional to study a little bit
about our teachers life and how he
started the lamrim tradition he didn't
he wasn't the first Marmion teacher the
Buddha was the first woman teacher but
historically he's the one from who came
from India to Tibet and and spread that
teaching
secondly we studied the greatness of the
teaching there are certain things about
this teaching work which are amazing and
for example if you study the alarm M in
order then you could see emptiness
directly you could have that perception
of bodhichitta that we talked about
yesterday okay
what do you call it slot a slot machine
okay
cheering ending the children ehe pursue
protocol in english means what's the
proper method protocol means proper
method and this is called in lamium it's
called me and she ninja means there's
rules about how to teach it and how to
study it
okay there's rules for the teacher and
there's rules for the students okay so
that's called protocol there's a very
strict tradition of how you teach it and
how you studying okay so when you study
lamium before you start an army you
study about teaching you study how do we
teach and how do we learn what are the
rules in buddhism for studying and
learning and teaching okay
last one then you can double your
kilometer to your mom then you actually
start to love em okay so these are the
traditional steps number one you talk
about the person who helped start the
moment number two you talk about how
cool is the teaching in general number
three you talk about the proper way to
teacher and to study it and then you
start the lemon okay this is the
tradition okay
what's the picture I don't remember oh
Ken remember Jay okay all right okay
item number ninety is Lord Aisha and we
said routes training and mission then in
this Lamia that we've been studying
there's a very long life story of Lord
Aisha who brought the long rim to Tibet
and I would like to I'd like to go
through some of his life it might take
the rest of the time this morning okay
so I'd like to go through we studied it
already I think many of you were not
there and I'm just gonna do highlights
of his life okay we can't cover his
whole life but I think it's interesting
how he developed himself and then how he
started to teach okay maybe you can
think about it for yourself you know if
you want to be an ACI teacher
maybe you should go through the same
kind of steps that he went through okay
here we go then traditionally his life
is divided and I'm just gonna skip
through his biography because it's very
long and we don't have time to do it
again Rick plans himself urkki worship
it so Kendall are you and Tanya - Nene
temple arch our debits alone so you know
where did he grow up
how was he born what was his family
first one I call it roots second part
how was he trained okay what kind of
teachings did he attend what kind of
teaches did he get in his life okay and
then third one is mission then what did
he do after he became a teacher after he
became qualified then what did he do and
all of us are the same in this room
everyone who wants to be an ACI teacher
I think we're very lucky because we have
such a rich variety of people here we
have people from many countries we have
people of many different kinds of
personality we have big businessmen we
have artists we have musicians we have
all kinds of people and so you have
different roots right then training how
should you train yourself and then
you're gonna have your teaching career
you know maybe people will talk about
the speed turnings of the wheel by Peter
and Marcia in their life okay so let's
look at his life story and as we go
through it don't think about some Indian
who lived a thousand years ago think
about your story okay alright and I'm
just gonna go through the highlights of
his life he was born in Bangalore which
is probably Bengal nowadays and he was
born into a royal family he was a prince
they had thirty five thousand subjects
which is a big city in his time they had
a golden palace grew up in a golden
palace and extremely powerful family
okay so many of the buddhist saints had
the Karma to be born into very powerful
family
Kelsey to natal choking him I saw a COO
tumor at the age of 18 months he started
to study refuge and bodhichitta
okay he's a little bit ahead of us okay
when he was three he studied she means
comet astrology but in the old days this
was important it was a very exact
science and very difficult to learn and
he studied writing and he studied
Sanskrit he became a master of Sanskrit
at the age of three then they say at the
age of six he learned to distinguish
between the outer and the inner
he learned to distinguish between the
outer and the inner and that means
what's the difference between Buddhist
philosophy and other kinds of philosophy
but what are the ideas that are
different between Buddhism and other
philosophies and he mastered it and they
say he was one of the few people there
were only three people in India who got
it right which is a tesha Naropa and
Shanti ba and they made it joke Naropa
had passed away later then ah tisha had
gone to Tibet and there was only there
was only one person left in India who
clearly understood the difference okay
but he understood it at six
when he was a lemon
he discovered girlfriends and then he
decided it wasn't worth it
sixth grade right great sixth grade he
checked it out and he decided this is
not for me okay this is not what I want
to do and and a woman a young lady came
to him who was Terra in disguise and she
said come on loss of mashiki logic logic
macho macho carriage and dump it's a
long boat you want to bet on their power
coaching not suiting Gretchen new
plumbing you are potentially as powerful
as a as an elephant your spiritual life
could be as powerful as an elephant but
when you chained an elephant it's the
greatest loss when you chained up the
most powerful being it's a great loss so
don't waste your time with small things
you have a great future and you should
you should try to help the world not
just enjoy yourself okay today is the
day that Jesus was crucified right and
there's a tradition that when he started
to teach he was taken out into the
desert for forty days he fasted and
tried to pray and the devil came to him
and showed him all the riches of the
world and said this can be yours if you
want this can be yours and the same very
similar tradition in Buddhism that at a
certain
aged people are offered great wealth
great fame and these great Saints give
it up these great Saints say no I that's
not all I want to be I want to be more
than that
so for him it was around would I say 12
years old 11 when he was in lemon so he
faced this same decision when he was 11
years old and he decided not to be a
famous king or or to spend his time in
pleasure okay then they say he left the
palace with a hundred and thirty cavalry
officers horse soldiers with him and he
went looking for a llama okay so I guess
he's 12 years old and his bodyguard is
130 horse guards and he went out to the
forest and he met a famous Buddhist
teacher named Jerry Zaatari and he
taught him he gave him refuge vows okay
and then he said you should go meet this
Lama at the London monastery which is
north east east northeast India and his
name is bode Bhadra chant you symbol and
you should go study with him so he did
maybe he's 13 something take down some
jade and diamond nine a monkey Lama duty
then he taught him about bodhichitta and
he gave him the third kind of teaching
what do we say
shubao
remember dumb not bad yeah he said you
go get personal advices not formal
teaching from a llama named Albert Ooty
okay our duty
what's our duty yeah it's the John John
my is called ever duty okay as I
remember our duty means to throw off you
know like take it off get it off okay
and we first the world these two
channels Pingala it and you take them
off so all the she moves to the central
channel so that llamas name is throw off
the side channels the teacher's name was
throw off the side channel which is the
goal of yoga for example okay okay yeah
Bianca Corrigan Kelsey Sanjana chipper
loophole not Jim but silicon Shana then
the is mom and dad said look the job of
a prince is to build temples give
charity to the poor and make offerings
to the three jewels it's not that Kings
are meant to become monks or become
spiritual practitioners okay and so
you're kind of it's okay to be spiritual
and they were spiritual but they said
you're not doing it the right way you
shouldn't do it that way Gail sila
chopping no one to Sammy Maga then he
said to his parents to tell you the
truth there's nothing about this palace
that's interesting to me and I don't
want to be a king doctor for me it's the
same as
the food you serve in this palace is the
same to me as eating rotten dogs meat
and all the silk you guys all wear
I don't have any attraction to it so he
he kind of had a way to Colin tension
with his parents
okay all right
table attention Sandia one current key
new opportunity no jealousy super ninja
to some location the copper tube okay in
the old days with special people it
would happen that they would get tantric
initiation first and then they would
study the great books later okay so ACI
we do it you know you learned the
subjects first open subjects and then
later you learn the secret teachings but
if the person special there is a
tradition to give them bad Rhianna first
so RT showers like that any met tantric
teacher and he got the name
yes she saw her yes she saw it on a
secret wisdom diamond okay and he
studied with a tantric Lama name Rahula
I like this one this is kind of weird
this is what we did in the hippie times
so Aatish I went and studied with the
stunting Lama and with some of his
friends and they all came back to the
palace dressed like tan Turkish so and
they were dancing and singing and acting
a little crazy and the parents were
really upset but they loved their son so
they let him stay in the palace but it
was a little bit crazy because they are
they are doing like tantric rituals and
singing and dancing and the Paras were
really uncomfortable okay I think
there's some kind of message in there
it's interesting then they basically I
think it was a plan because they finally
the king and queen kicked him out and
said don't go back and then he was free
okay like he was embarrassing them so
they they kicked him out and from the
age of 21 to the age of 29 although
there's some debate about it maybe 28
he's studying with AMA duty and great
tantric master they have an interesting
expression in in Tibetan not an agenda
made but a chill made television did
tour he took all that power political
power and financial power that he had
and he spit it out like a a booger you
know at heart and to him it it means
that much all the money all the power he
just
and to him it it wasn't more important
than spit and this focuses that was
pretty amazing to give up so much power
and so much wealth like spit he
continued to study but Rajee honor
he started to get what he called bighead
he said oh I'm a real tantric master and
so the bikinis the lady angels came to
him and they showed him a huge library
of tantric books that he never saw
before they said you're not a tantric
master look you never even saw these
books before so he got they put him in
his place okay
[Music]
then one of his tentacle of us that you
know if you really want to help the
world you should become a monk which is
a cool statement okay we think that
first you become a monk and then you
should become a tantric are but in this
case is one of his tantric teachers
Rahul Gupta told him look if you really
want to help people it's not enough to
be at under God you should be a monk
also and so he became a monk at the age
of 29 which is pretty wrong so nowadays
in the monastery
you know kids go there at seven they get
first ordination around 15 and at 21
they become a full month but I think
there's something important that etosha
who's kind of like the grandfather of
our whole tradition waited until he was
almost thirty and you're talking in a
culture where people live to forty you
see so he was three-quarters to his life
before he became a mom so it means it
was a very serious step in those days
[Music]
eventually he studied with a hundred and
fifty seven teachers
and then he met a teacher named Tommy
rakshita okay whose text sages
translating and with him he studied you
know that text is very almost tantric
but what did he study with demonic Sita
is vinaya the whole vinaya we call long
day she and lumba yeah I'll be dumber
he studied I'll be Thomas so you think
you know when you read that poem it
seems like drama rakshita must have been
instantly teacher or something but it
turns out he was his teacher for the
foundation subjects the nya and AB Adama
okay and they studied chair dr. Shepherd
which is a detailed explanation which is
why the Detailers are called Detailers
okay so in those days it was common to
teach from this abhidharma book mmm
bump oh yeah yeah 800 chapters to that
book okay and he studied it for 12 years
with dominar kita okay and then when he
left for Tibet to teach tamil archita
gave him the kind of knife I like this
part in his life a lot I think I even
put it in the loge on course I don't
remember but he was hanging out in
Bodhgaya
okay which was called Vajrasana at that
time a seed of the diamond and two women
two beautiful ladies were flying through
the sky
okay and he's like whoa
you know and they were yelling at each
other you know and one of them said hey
if I want to get enlightened really fast
you know what should I study and the
other said bodhichitta bodhichitta then
he's like mmm you know he got this sign
okay
then he was add a special wall which was
built by the gardener around the Bodhi
tree because the Bodhi tree was getting
eaten up by elephants and stuff so at
that time there was a famous wall built
by Nagarjuna to protect the Bodhi tree
and there was an old lady and a young
lady and they were sitting against the
wall and a young one asked the old one
if I wanted to get enlightened really
fast like what would be the best way and
the old one said oh you gotta study
bodhichitta you should study buddies you
know and then a third thing he was doing
Gondo kora means become circumambulating
the whole boat Gaia stupa which we can
still do we did it we all went as a
group not long ago 1999 and so he was
walking around the stupa and there was a
there was a Buddha statue and it started
talking to him and it said hey if you
really want to get enlightened fast you
got a study buddy chitter you know so
these aren't three oh looks like there's
another one mm-hmm yeah and it happened
again with another image so he thought
well that I guess
means I should study bodhichitta and he
started to check around if there was a
good teacher who could teach bodhichitta
and he heard about lama sterling ba sue
sue sue van de vivir guru
okay Silvana De Vita which means Sumatra
in the old days so he got information
that if he went to Indonesia what they
call golden island is that where we're
going gentlemen we're going to Bali for
the lamium in December so you guys
should come because it's very close to
where our teacher got the instructions
on bodhichitta and besides that it's a
beautiful beach I think that's more
important we went there with the
Indonesia group recently it was quite
beautiful and I think it's a good karma
to study those subjects where they were
taught so if you have time talk to
Jasmine about it so he heard about this
lama called
lama of the golden island sumatra and he
decided he would go request the
teachings on bodhichitta and he got in a
boat and they went for thirteen months
okay
and in those days extremely dangerous
very small survival rate then they had
lots of adventures whales and sharks
tried to tip over the boat and special
lightning storms and and Ottershaw
would always stand in the front of the
boat and do prayers and then they they
made it took 13 months okay
they say it there's an interesting thing
they say the bunker says look you and me
if we go out of the monastery for a
couple of days we change our clothes we
put on lay clothes but during those 13
months on the ship partition never took
office he didn't wear normal clothes he
always wore his monk robe and that's the
next item what is the next item 91 I
think it's a bunch of DCI teachers like
Peter and Masha dressed up in nice
clothes and suits and stuff and this is
very much something that our teacher
would have done you know he thought it
was very important to dress the part
when you're a teacher so he and there's
many stories about him making sure his
monks were naughty naughty means like
you know looking very nice and there's
many stories of him encouraging his
students when they teach to look
professional I don't mean an ACI teacher
should wear a suit and tie I think it
might be uncomfortable for its students
but you should look nice okay there's a
tradition that when you teach the Dharma
you should look nice okay you shouldn't
look like a bum you know you didn't
shave or you didn't do your hair or
something like to respect the Dharma
it's a tradition too to dress nicely and
and to look nice for your students okay
and you know we're Buddhists and we
think dressing nice isn't very important
but it is important when you're a
teacher okay
you should make a good impression if
your students parents came to the talk
would they be happy okay that's that's a
good way to think about it I personally
don't like to dress up at all I really
enjoy old jeans my jeans are all really
old and I like old shirts the shirts I
wear sometimes in the evening I got in
the goodwill and I like them because
they're soft and but when we go to teach
DCI I put on this ridiculous suit and a
tie and it's for the demo okay it's not
for your comfort okay so you should look
nice when you teach okay you don't have
to look fancy but you should look clean
and nice if your students parents came
would they be happy cute under camera
and then when he got to by the way I
might go over a few minutes okay when he
got to Sumatra I think I told you a
different time but it was 14 days he
didn't go to see this llama for 14 days
he met all of his students and he asked
questions and he investigated the
teacher I think nowadays it would be on
the Internet
you would investigate the teacher okay
and he investigated that teacher for
fourteen days before I even went to his
house so if it's you and me we will jump
off the boat and run to the teachers
house after 13 months but he you know he
gave us an example that we should be
picky about the teacher and we should
investigate the teacher check them okay
mmm almost done
the first book he studied with that
teacher 15 days of teaching was the
jewel of realizations okay
a song as text where we got the Lions
dance from okay then he spent then he
got sold and he spent 12 years there he
stayed with that teacher for 12 years
okay $500 word okay you ready
cuz I know you're never gonna get it
Nadel mmm okay forget it anyway you'll
never forget it in the future oh it's
easy
tell us easy but now you'll never get it
okay
let's give up you give up yeah okay it
means you're ahead name means your
pillow
okay name means your pillow gentlemen's
so for 12 years they were as close as
your head is to your pillow it's kind of
a sweet way to say they were inseparable
okay so he spent 12 years there and
studied the teachings on bodhichitta and
the teacher said it's time for you to go
do your thing in the land of snows and
Aisha had no idea what he was talking
about I think we stopped there it goes
on quite a bit okay I'm gonna stop there
we'll do it more tomorrow
okay
[Music]
we mark SaLuSa you ready
she in banking party son Gary
[Music]
he nurtured by cho young-nam and i'll
come to come he didn't care walk on the
Sun Amish a torsion tsunami a nature
Tombaugh corny dog home